League of Women Voters of Rensselaer County Records apap103
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Troy City Government, 1939-2004; Undated; 5; 0.85 cubic ft.
  - City Charter, 1994 (Box 2 (5-Troy City Government), Folder 19)
  - City Charter and Abolishing the Bureau of Police, 1995 (Box 2 (5-Troy City Government), Folder 20)
  - City Council, League of Women Voters Statements on Budget, 1995 (Box 2 (5-Troy City Government), Folder 21)
  - Troy Council/Charter, 1996 (Box 2 (5-Troy City Government), Folder 22)
  - Troy Charter, 1998 (Box 2 (5-Troy City Government), Folder 23)
  - Troy Government and Redistricting, 2001 (Box 2 (5-Troy City Government), Folder 24)
  - Troy Charter, 2004 (Box 2 (5-Troy City Government), Folder 25)
- Voter Services, 1943-2007; Undated; 6; 1.60 cubic ft.
  Series 6 contains information about Voter Services. Voter Services is the League's most active program, whereby they register people to vote, sponsor election debates, publish literature about candidates and citizens' rights as voters, and oversee the local electoral process in hopes of keeping the process fair and the citizenry well-educated about their rights and responsibilities as voters. This series contains various oversized items, including the League's Election and Voter Guides that were often published as supplements in the local papers. The League advocated high school students' participation in local elections and permanent personal registration. They were also involved in the Troy Housing Authority, Troy Public Library, and Rensselaer School elections. Activities ranged from voter registration, to candidate questionnaires to flyers and pamphlets that provided basic information about voting and the candidates.
  - Voters Service, 1943-1949 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 1)
  - Voters Service, 1950-1955 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 2)
  - Permanent Personal Registration, 1956-1958 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 3)
  - Voters Service, 1956-1960 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 4)
  - Voters Service, 1961-1965 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 5)
  - Map of Troy's Seven City Council Districts, 1961-1965 (Oversized 1, Folder 12)
  - Registration Poster, 1966-1967 (Oversized 1, Folder 13)
  - Voters Service, 1966-1967 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 6)
  - Permanent Personal Registration, 1966-1967 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 7)
  - Voters Service, 1968-1969 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 8)
  - Voter's Guides, Flyers, and Election Ballot, 1968-1969 (Oversized 2, Folder 4)
  - Flyers and Absentee Voter's Ballot, 1970 (Oversized 2, Folder 5)
  - Voters Service, 1970 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 9)
  - Flyers, Absentee Voter's Ballot, and Newspaper Article, 1971 (Oversized 2, Folder 6)
  - Voters Service, 1971 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 10)
  - Voters Service, 1972 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 11)
  - Voter's Guide, Absentee Voter's Ballot, and a Newspaper Article about the Election, 1972 (Oversized 2, Folder 7)
  - Judicial Ethics of Judicial Candidates, 1972-1975 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 12)
  - Flyers and Pamphlets, 1972-1986 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 13)
  - High School Registration, 1973 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 14)
  - Various Local Newspapers Offering Election Guides and Facts, 1973 (Oversized 2, Folder 8)
  - Voters Service, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 15)
  - Voters Guide Newspapers, 1974-1975 (Oversized 1, Folder 14)
  - Voters Service, 1976 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 16)
  - Candidates Questionnaire, 1976-1986 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 17)
  - Voters Service, 1977 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 18)
  - Questionnaire prepared by the LWVRC and Answered by East Greenbush Candidates, 1977 (Oversized 2, Folder 9)
  - Election Guide, 1978-1979 (Oversized 2, Folder 10)
  - Voters Service, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 19)
  - Facts for Voters, 1978-1986 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 20)
  - Speakers, 1979-1980; 1983-1984 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 21)
  - Voters Service, 1980-1983 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 22)
  - Candidate Forums, 1981-1989 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 23)
  - Polling Places and Enrollment Information, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 24)
  - General Planning, 1983-1986 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 25)
  - "Easy to Read Voter Registration Facts for New York State, 1984 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 26)
  - Candidates Meeting, School Board, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 27)
  - Voters Service, 1984 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 28)
  - Election Guide, 1984-1986 (Oversized 2, Folder 11)
  - Voter Registration, 1984-1998 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 30)
  - Voters Service, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 31)
  - Flyers and Pamphlets, 1988-2005 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 32)
  - Making Democracy Work Committee, 1990 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 33)
  - Troy Public Library Forum and Election, 1990 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 34)
  - Voters Service, 1990 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 35)
  - Troy Housing Authority Elections, 1992 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 36)
  - Voting in Rensselaer County, College Students, 1992 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 37)
  - High School Participation in Government Local Elections, 1993 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 38)
  - Voters Service, 1993 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 39)
  - Voter's Guide, 1993 (Oversized 1, Folder 15)
  - Voters Service, 1994 (Box 1 (6-Voter Services), Folder 40)
  - Voters Service, 1995 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 1)
  - Rensselaer County Election Results, 1995-1996 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 2)
  - Governing at the Grassroots Conference, 1996 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 3)
  - Making Democracy Work Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 4)
  - League of Women Voters Skit for Literary Volunteers Program, 1997 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 5)
  - Making Democracy Work Committee, 1998 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 6)
  - Voter Guide, 1999 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 7)
  - Making Democracy Work Committee, 1999 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 8)
  - Voter's Guide, 1999 (Oversized 2, Folder 12)
  - Voters Service, 2001 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 9)
  - Voters Service, 2004 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 10)
  - Electronic Voting in New York State, 2005-2006; Undated (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 11)
  - Voters Service, 2007 (Box 2 (6-Voter Services), Folder 12)
- Subject Files, 1923-2008; Undated; 7; 0.60 cubic ft.
  Series 7, Subject Files, consists of a more general and broader overview of the LWVRC's programs and activities. The series contains newspaper clippings from 1974 to 1993 on issues surrounding politics and schools, county apportionment, human resources, financing public higher education, investment in developing countries, the New York State Budget Process, public health, redistricting, Troy housing and Troy police court.
  - League of Women Voters of Rensselaer County Chapter History, 1923; 1938; 1964; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Tema Bellinson Memorial, 1955; 1970; 1994 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - National Study, Investment in Developing Countries, 1963 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - State Study, Reapportionment, ca. 1964 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - County Study, Human Resources, 1968 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence about Up the Ladder, 1969 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - 50th Anniversary of the Founding of the League Women Voters of the United States, 1970 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Air Pollution Consensus Conducted by National League Women of Voters, 1971 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Troy Housing, 1973 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Local Government in New York State, ca. 1974 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Clippings about Politics, 1974-1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Clippings about the League of Women Voters in General, 1974-1993 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977-1978; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Howard and Bush Proposal, 1980-1981 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - County Apportionment, 1980-1986 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Public Meeting, Federal Tax Reform Proposals, 1985 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Recycling Speaker, 1987 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Student League of Voters at Russell Sage College, an Affiliate of League of Women Voters, 1989-1998; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18-19)
  - Redistricting/Reapportionment, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - New York State Budget Process, Background Material, 1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - New York State Budget Process, "Budget Watch", 1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - New York State Budget Process, Committee and Meeting Notes, 1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - New York State Budget Process, Consensus Questions, 1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - New York State Budget Process, State Board Reports, 1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - New York State Budget Process, State Committee Notes, 1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - New York State Budget Process The Voter, 1992 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Troy Police Court, 1993 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Public Health, 1994 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Mobilization for Our Children, State Communities Aid Association, 1995 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Local Government Conference, 1996 January 12-1996 January 13 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Financing Public Education, 1996 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - State Commission on the Capital Region, 1996 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - New York State Constitutional Convention Correspondence, 1997 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Financing Public Higher Education, 1997-1999 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Archives in the Troy Public Library, 1998 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Informations and Nominations Sent to League of Women Voters of New York State, 2002-2008 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
- Video and Audio Tapes, 1970-1997; 8; 0.4 cubic ft.
  Series 8 is made up of audio/visual tapes. There are 5 VHS tapes (1995-1997). In 1995, the League hosted a panel discussion on environmental issues. In 1996, it hosted a public information meeting on financing education and a workshop on the 1996 election. In 1997, it hosted a candidates' forum and a meet the candidates' panel. In addition, the series also includes a 7.5 speed dual track reel of a discussion between Beulah Bailey Thull, the LWVRC's first president, and Mary Stierer, LWVRC president from 1969-71 concerning the city manager form of government, Troy politics and history, the suffrage movement and voter registration. The discussion was for Paul Flanigan's radio show (WTRY) in 1970. There are also 2 UCA60 videocassettes about the 1980 election for Troy mayor. Finally the series contains 3 60-minute audiotapes labeled the "History Project." Taped in 1982, the cassettes are interviews with Ruth Binder, Eva Levy and Mary Stierer, past League leaders.
  - Beulah Bailey Thull and Mary Stierer, two Presidents of the LWVRC, discuss Troy Government, 1970 (Reel 1)
  - "Election 80 - Mayor or Manager for City of Troy", 1980 (Video-tape 1-2)
  - LWVRC History Project, Ruth Binder, 1982 August 05 (Cassette 1)
  - LWVRC History Project, Eva Levy, 1982 August 10 (Cassette 2)
  - LWVRC History Project, Mary Stierer, 1982 August 23 (Cassette 3)
  - Untitled Videotape, 1995 October 26 (Video-tape 3)
  - Public Info. Meeting on Financing Education, 1996 March 28 (Video-tape 4)
  - Getting Into Issues - 1996 Election", 1996 September 24 (Video-tape 5)
  - Election 1997, Candidates Forum for County Clerk, District Attorney, and County Executive, 1997 October 08 (Video-tape 6)
  - Meet the Candidate, Troy Council, 1997 October 23 (Video-tape 7)